<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NAS on KK's Blog (fromkk)</title><link>https://www.fromkk.com/tags/nas/</link><description>Recent content in NAS on KK's Blog (fromkk)</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 22:56:51 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fromkk.com/tags/nas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Run Synology in QNAP NAS with PVE</title><link>https://www.fromkk.com/posts/run-synology-in-qnap-nas-with-pve/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 20:53:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.fromkk.com/posts/run-synology-in-qnap-nas-with-pve/</guid><description>&lt;p>Three years ago, I bought a QNAP TS-453Dmini NAS. Although it has a slow WEB UI and slow restart, it still fits my needs as all of the applications I need are running in Docker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, I want to move some files from my Mac to NAS to save space. I need a application behave like Dropbox, which can show all the files in the NAS and only download the files I need. I have tried the QSync, but it does not have thumbnails for cloud image and it does not have icons to show the file status. I also tried the &lt;a href="https://www.seafile.com/home/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer">Seafile&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s a powerful application, which requires 4G RAM to run, and there is bug in the thumbnail. I used to have a Synology ARM NAS, the Synology Drive has all the features I need, so I want to run it on my QNAP NAS. After some research, I managed to run Synology and QNAP together on my NAS. Here is the guide.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QNAP TS-453Dmini Review</title><link>https://www.fromkk.com/posts/qnap-ts-453bmini-review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:17:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.fromkk.com/posts/qnap-ts-453bmini-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>My first NAS is Synology DS120j, which is ARM based entry level product. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to use it for downloading and backup, but not power enough for running docker and virtual machine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I bought this NAS last month, and I&amp;rsquo;m satisfied with it. Here are the advantages and disadvantages.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>